<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Emil Kaskikallio Portfolio</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Emil Kaskikallio Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 14:04:20 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio website using HUGO framework and github pages</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 14:04:20 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I wanted to create a portfolio page with the following features.&#xA;Interactive Easy to update and maintain Easy to host, prefferably for free No need to compile or download anything to view High level of customization Why I chose HUGO? Hugo generates a static website which can be hosted through GitHub pages for free, perfect for personal portfolio. It is very light, fast and customizable and often used for writing documentation so I figured it could be usefull to learn.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Erlang based chat application using distributed systems.</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/erlchat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 14:54:57 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/erlchat/</guid>
      <description>This is a screenshot from the app with two clients messaging. The info mesage is received by both clients when connected to the server. After that the client on the left has sent a message which the client on the right has received&#xD;ErlChat is a web application for simple text based chat application developped using a highly concurrent programming language Erlang. This project combines my knowledge in distributed computing with Erlang, websocket communication protocols and dynamic Vue.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cycling data tracking withArduino and BLE</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/arduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 14:23:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/arduino/</guid>
      <description>View this post on Instagram A post shared by Emil (@emilechoes)&#xA;Arduino cycling computer is my first larger project implemented with Arduino Nano RP2040 Connect microcontroller. It combines my skills with embedded systems, C++ programming, Arduino code, Electrical work, Soldering and 3D-printing.&#xA;The Project Implementation This project implements a standalone device for measuring basic cycling related metrics such as speed, cadence, distance and average speed. This project was implemented using the board Arduino Nano RP2040 Connect which allows this device to communicate with third party fitness apps such as Wahoo fitness using BLE standards for cadence and speed sensors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DIY Bird Spotting Camera</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/birdspotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 13:34:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/birdspotting/</guid>
      <description>During the winter holiday I wanted to film some birds in my back yard. Filming birds however can be really tedious as you have to be really close inorder to get a good shot, and inorder to get that close the bird should not be able to detect you. However I managed to get some good shots with a DIY setup of my own:&#xA;Näytä tämä julkaisu Instagramissa Henkilön Emil (@emilechoes) jakama julkaisu</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
